Finding Aid for the Joseph Mullendore Music Manuscripts LSC.2243
UCLA Library Special Collections
Joseph Mullendore music manuscripts
circa 1930s - 1960s
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mullendore, Joseph
LSC.2243
2 Linear Feet (5 flat boxes)
Collection consists of assorted music manuscripts related to the career of music composer Joseph Mullendore.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stephanie Webb, 2013.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7420861
Biography
Joseph Milton Mullendore Jr. was born in Philadelphia, PA on October 21, 1914. He was educated at Philadelphia Conservatory. He began his career in film and television as an arranger, often scoring the compositions of his colleague Herschel Burke Gilbert (and others). In the early 1950s, he began scoring and arranging for motion pictures such as The Jackie Robinson Story (1950), New York Confidential (1955), While the City Sleeps (1956), and The Shaggy Dog (1959). He also composed and conducted music scores for a number of popular television programs such as Burke's Law, Honey West, Lost In Space, The Rifleman, Twilight Zone, and Zane Grey Theatre, among others. He was nominated for an Emmy award in the 1962-1963 for his work on The Dick Powell Theater. Joe Mullendore died on June 19, 1990 in Pasadena, CA.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of assorted music manuscripts related to the career of music composer Joseph Mullendore and a small amount of published sheet music written by others. Included are materials representing the television programs The Dick Powell Show and Zane Grey Theater, a small amount of printed sheet music featuring Sid Robin, and scores by Mullendore and others.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder titles.
Mullendore, Joseph
- Assorted scores by Mullendore, 1959-1960s (Box 4)
- Aquamarine Rhapsody / Moon Serenade, c. 1931-1932 (Box 3)
- Bolero, no date (Box 1)
- Bolero - onion skin score and parts, no date (Box 3)
- Composition Sketches and Unfinished Manuscripts, no dates (Box 5)
  General note
  With published material about Hammond organs.
- Conductor scores, 1950s, no dates (Box 5)
  With Blues in 3, Tomorrow the Man, The Three Bears and Argentina, among others.
- Dick Powell Show (The) - Library Set no. 2; 4700 through 47125, 1961 (Box 2)
- James Thurber Mischraum, 1961 (Box 3)
- Joe and Josie, 1962 (Box 4)
- L. Stevens scores, 1959 (Box 5)
- McKeever and the Colonel, 1960 (Box 4)
- Mickey Mouse Club, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
  Appears to be from the Mickey Mouse Club.
- New York Confidential - cue music spiral bound folio, ca. 1951 (Box 1)
- Parade of the Chessmen - condensed score, no date (Box 1)
- Piano Quintet - five spiral bound folios, no date (Box 1)
  Piano, Viola, Cello, Violins I and II.
- Robert Taylor Detectives - extra scores 2800, no date (Box 3)
- Sheet music by Sid Robin, 1930s, 1940s, 1950s (Box 1)
- Themes and Songs by Joseph Mullendore - spiral bound notebook, no date (Box 1)
- This is My Moment, no date (Box 3)
  Holograph lines.
- Wicked Woman / When I Was One and Twenty - sheet music, no date (Box 1)
- Zane Grey - Library Set no. 2; 2600, no date (Box 3)